# **CHRISTOPHER DO**

chris.n.do@gmail.com (813) 990-7318

# **Professional Summary**

Engineering and IT professional with a MSEE and 10 years of professional experience. Excels at adapting to new technologies in a changing environment. Excellent teamwork, leadership, and communication skills. Looking for opportunities involving consulting, technical project management, or solutions architect roles. Always looking for ways that cloud technology and information security can improve in an organization. Thrives in a challenging, collaborative, constantly changing environment with a knack for finding solutions and completing tasks ahead of schedule.

•	ΙT	and	Engin	eering	Know	led	lge

- Leadership and Supervision
- Scripting (Javascript/Python)

# • Risk Management Framework

- Agile and DevOps
- Systems Development Life Cycle
- Project Management
- Information Systems Security
- Cloud Computing

#### **Education**

• MSEE (MS in Electrical Engineering) – University of South Florida

• BSEE (BS in Electrical Engineering) – University of Florida

2011

# 2009

#### Certifications

- CISSP Certified Info System Security Professional ISC2
- CISM Certified Information Security Manager ISACA
- **CEH** Certified Ethical Hacker EC-Council
- CCSK (v4) Certificate of Cloud Security Knowledge CSA
- CSM Certified Scrum Master CSA

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect (Associate)
- AWS Certified SysOps Administrator (Associate)
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- ITIL (v3) Info Technology Infrastructure Library Axelos

#### **Experience**

## Senior Cloud Security Engineer – Booz Allen Hamilton

Sep 2018 to Present

- Managed security operations and compliance for a federal client utilizing Amazon Web Services (AWS) to provide platform for tenants to develop, run, and manage applications in an Agile environment.
- Implemented and automated security processes shift security to the left to align with a DevSecOps framework.
- Ensured compliance with Federal standards such as FISMA and FedRAMP utilizing NIST SP 800-37 and NIST SP 800-53.
- Worked with engineers to architect secure systems that aligned with compliance standards.
- Created and maintained security and compliance documentation that shaped the security policies of the growing platform.
- Automated the vulnerability management process using scripts, reducing manual analysis time by over 99%. Automated other various documentation and security processes using Javascript or Python.
- Implemented new security tools to enhance our DevSecOps pipeline to have a secure-by-design foundation.
- Tools used: Jira, Confluence, G Suite (Google), Tenable Nessus, Twistlock, Netsparker, AWS, RedHat Linux, Google Apps Scripts/Javascript, Python.

## IT Specialist / IT Management (GS-13) – US Patent & Trademark Office

May 2016 to Sep 2018

- Contributed to projects supporting over 16,000 users on a multi-billion dollar production enterprise network, consulting on highly visible projects to deliver results ahead of schedule and under budget.
- Information Systems Security Officer Served as assistant ISSO for our division. Involved POA&M Remediation, vulnerability scan analysis, baseline requirements, coordination of NIST and FedRAMP Requirements. Maintained system boundary for proper patching and controls to meet compliance guidelines. Enforced USGCB Standards. Assisted in Security Impact Analysis and software testing.
- Agile Product Owner and Scrum Master experience working with development team, operations team, and customers to facilitate and encourage Agile methodologies using the Scrum Framework for Windows 10 migration, consulted with business groups to get applications assessed, remediated, and tested. Worked with development team to create user stories for tracking and remediating issues.
- Desktop Engineering Managed incoming support tickets and managed a group of contractors to assist in resolving any issues that users had. This involved consulting with manufacturers and vendors to find solutions. Also worked with Active Directory (AD) and Group Policy Objects (GPO's).
- Software Patching/Packaging Managed system administrators to deploy patches and packages on a regular basis to keep up to date with government security standards imposed by our cybersecurity group. Consulted with appropriate business groups to schedule application deployments to over 16,000 users. Included Software testing/licensing maintenance.

- Technical Lead/Administrator Served as the administrator for Symantec Endpoint Protection and Commvault Backup & Recovery solutions. Worked on the system architecture as well as the policies required to meet our needs. Consulted with various groups to gather requirements, including server, network, storage, and hardware teams.
- Project Management Consulted on various projects in order to determine requirements, perform market research, create matrices, consult with vendors, perform cost analysis, developed architecture, implemented solutions, and closed out projects. Projects: Windows 10 Migration, Symantec Endpoint Protection, Commvault Endpoint Data Backup, BelArc, Skype for Business, in addition, countless government in-house applications (GOTS/AIS).
- Tools: MS Office 365 Suite, MS Windows 7/10, MS Server 2008/2016, MS SharePoint, MS SCCM, Tenable Nessus, Commvault Data Backup

## Patent Examiner / Electrical Engineering (GS-13) – US Patent & Trademark Office

Sept 2012 to May 2016

- Review patent applications for compliance with all laws and regulations.
- Examine applicant's detailed drawings as represented as electrical schematics, 3-dimensional mechanical models, and chemical manufacturing processes.
- Make recommendations to applicants and businesses regarding patent applications and patent content.
- Prepare Office Actions that clearly evaluate and explain problems within an applicant's patent application.
- Investigate each application to ascertain that the invention is described clearly and in such a way that a skilled person would be able to use it.
- Analyze disclosures and claims for compliance with 35 USC 101,102,103 and 112 laws.
- Maintain up-to-date knowledge of developments through study and visits to laboratories, factories, exhibitions and seminars.
- Examine legal matters affecting acceptability and entitlement to the monopoly claimed by the applicant.
- Specialized in the computer memory area, which led to becoming in expert in the art.

### Systems Engineer (GS-12) – Robins AFB

July 2010 to Sept 2012

- ALQ-161 Electronic Warfare system for the B-1B: Involved in learning about how the ALQ-161 system works and helped in performing various system tests involving jamming and stress tests using different software in a lab environment.
- Worked on software called ERS (Emitter Reprogramming Software) that created an Emitter Identification Database (EID) that was loaded onto the PFS, which was the preprocessor flight software for the ALQ-161. ERS was written in C# and tasking included writing methods and debugging/testing as well as writing many unit tests. Some tasks included software testing and troubleshooting which involved running test data sheets that would run through every step of the software and look for bugs or errors, and if there were any, I had to determine where the issue was in the code. I also had to write many of these unit tests for the software and organize them into PowerPoint's so that someone else could run through the unit test efficiently. We would often use virtual machine's to run tests on various operating systems to see if the software we were working on was compatible across multiple operating systems. This software involved working with a client who had a strict list of requirements and deadlines, and we had to work together with contractors and government employee's in order to meet the requirements of the client.
- Involved in project involving a collaborative effort between military services and Electronic Warfare information. The project goal was to create a DOD-wide website with databases of information from all the services as a one-stop-shop for EW Information.
- Worked on prototype system to replace a portion of the DCGS ISR (Distributed Common Ground System Intelligence, Surveillance and Reconnaissance) system. We spoke with many different vendors (NetApp, EMC, Dell, etc) to learn about the different virtual storage options. These vendors came to us to work with us and help us figure out if their storage options fit the criteria we needed for our prototype system. Worked on configuring systems for the prototype that included Solaris, Redhat, Windows Server 2008, Windows 7 through virtual machines created to test the different operating systems and tools available on them. Also used tools such as VMWare, VSphere, VCenter, ESXi, and VMWare View on storage systems. I worked with workstations, zero clients, thin clients, thick clients, server blades, and other storage solutions.
- Took many training courses involving systems engineering, acquisitions, management, diminishing sources, logistics, electronic warfare, and various hardware courses.